# David Basalla - Full stack web developer

Email: davidbasalla@gmail.com | Website: davidbasalla.com | Address: Brussels, BE



## **Skills**

# Languages:

Ruby, JavaScript, Python

#### Frameworks:

Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, React, ExpressJS, Flask, PyQt

#### **Databases:**

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, ElasticSearch, Redis

### **Testing/TDD:**

RSpec, Cucumber, Jest, Cypress, Selenium

#### CI/CD:

Jenkins, CircleCI, Buildkite

#### **Hosting:**

AWS, Terraform, Docker, OpenShift k8s, Linux

#### 3D Graphics:

Maya, Photoshop, Nuke, Mari, MEL, Renderman, OpenGL, WebGL

# Languages:

English - Native German - Native Danish - Advanced French - Intermediate

### **About me**

I am a professional full stack web developer with 7+ years of experience as digital consultant and UK civil servant and 8 years' experience in movie visual effects. I have lived in UK, US, NZ, DK, DE and currently Belgium. Ruby on Rails, React and Docker are my current favourite tools, but I'm always looking to expand my skills with which I can craft compelling digital experiences for users. I enjoy working in agile, communicative teams.

# **Professional experience**

# Freelance Developer, Isabel Group, Brussels - 2019 - Current

Working on digital identity and signature solutions. See <a href="www.trulius.be">www.trulius.be</a> and <a href="www.trulius.

# Consultant Full Stack Developer, Red Badger, London - 2017 - 2019

Working as consultant full stack developer on projects for <u>HSBC</u> and <u>Fortnum & Mason</u> (primarily React, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, AWS).

# Developer, Government Digital Services (GDS), London - 2016 - 2017

Working on the <u>GOV.UK</u> (UK government's website) micro-service platform, primarily with Ruby on Rails. I was acting team tech lead for 4 months and received a <u>Civil Service Award bonus</u> for my performance.

# Developer, Unboxed Consulting, London - 2015 - 2016

Worked as consultant full stack developer (primarily Ruby on Rails), with focus on Agile delivery and TDD on multiple projects (<u>E-petitions for UK government</u> and contracting at <u>Government Digital Services</u>).

# 3D Technical Director & Sequence Supervisor, UK/NZ/US - 2005 - 2014

I worked in the Film Visual Effects industry, first as 3D artist/technical director, then as <u>team lead</u> and <u>sequence supervisor</u> (leading teams of 20-30 people). I worked on <u>Oscar award winning movies (Avatar, The Dark Knight)</u> at the top VFX companies in the world (<u>Weta Digital</u>, <u>Industrial Light & Magic</u> and <u>Double Negative</u>). Worked with Python, MEL and PyQt to write scripts.

#### **Education**

#### MSc Computer Science, Imperial College London - 2013 - 2014

<u>Completed with Distinction</u>, specialised in Algorithms, Databases, Graphics and Artificial Intelligence, experience with C++, Java, Prolog, PostgreSQL

#### BA & MSc Computer Animation, Bournemouth University - 2001 - 2005

Completed with Distinction, experience with C/C++ and OpenGL

# Side projects

### cinelandmarks.com, Berlin - 2018 - present

Built platform for independent cinemas (GatsbyJS, React, Contentful, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS)

### Physio an der Bucht, Berlin - 2012 - present

Built and maintaining staff management software and public website (Python, PyQt, MySQL, Jekyll, CircleCl)